有一个古老的日本寓言，
There's an old Japanese parable
讲述了一个陷入困境的战士，
about a troubled warrior who is haunted
被他在战斗中夺取的生命的幽灵所困扰。
by the ghosts of the lives he took in battle.
你是伟大的丝绸圣人吗？
Are you the great silk sage?
我必须知道天堂和地狱是否存在。
I must know if heaven and hell exist.
那么多人被屠杀了。
So many have been slaughtered.
对他们来说，我希望他们能进入天堂。
For them, I hope there is a heaven.
但我杀了那么多人，对我来说,
But I have killed so many, and for me,
我祈祷没有地狱。
I pray there is no hell.
求你了，我一定要知道！
Please, I must know!
我不想把这样的智慧浪费在
I would not want to waste such wisdom
你这样一个无情的懦夫身上。
on a heartless coward like you.
你说什么，老太婆？
What did you say, old woman?
你打算用那个做什么？
What did you intend to do with that?
杀一个手无寸铁的女人来证明你是个懦夫？
Prove that you're a coward by killing a defenseless woman?
我从未见过如此软弱的战士。
I've never seen such weakness in a warrior.
这就是地狱。
That is hell.
那就是天堂。
And that is heaven.
心的力量
我的名字是玛雅·安吉洛，
My name is Maya Angelou,
我相信心是我们生命中最有力量、
and I believe that the heart is the most forceful,
最有影响力的元素。
impactful element in our lives.
你将永远无法发挥其全部潜力，
You will never ever reach their full potential,
如果你不敞开心扉的话。
if you don't open your heart.
心的力量是
And the power of the heart is
在最深的层次上与「你是谁」联系密切。
to be connected with who you are at the deepest level.
我们在诗意的意义上想到了心，
We think of the heart in the poetic sense,
它是爱和慈悲心的栖息地。
the seat of love and compassion.
这颗心正是如此的重要。
And it's this heart that is so terribly important.
我是个作家。
I'm a writer.
对我来说，灵感是必不可少的。
For me, inspiration is essential.
创造力是必不可少的。
Creativity is essential.
而我只有通过心才能找到它们。
And I can only find it through the heart.
更高层次的逻辑和理解
The higher order of logic and understanding
源于你的内心。
originates in your heart.
它们是在你的心中所体验到的。
It's experienced in your heart.
它活在你的心里。
It's lived in your heart.
从我们出生到死亡，生理上的心脏
The physical heart pumps blood through the veins and arteries
通过静脉和动脉泵送血液。
from the time we're born until time we die.
它是有史以来效率最高的泵。
The most efficient pump ever invented.
但是，心脏的作用不仅仅如此。
But the heart is more than that.
我们在 HeartMath 做了个实验，
We did an experiment here at HeartMath
研究信息如何在
to study how the information flows
心脏和大脑之间流动，实际上我们
between the heart and the brain, and we actually
发现了一些非同寻常的东西,
discovered something quite remarkable,
让我们大吃一惊的东西。
something that surprised us.
研究中的参与者
The participants in the study were
被连接到各种传感器，
connected to various sensors
以测量他们的脑电波、心跳等。
to measure their brain waves, their heartbeats, and so on.
然后被展示成各种各样的图像。
And then they were exposed to various images.
有些是高度兴奋的，
Some were high arousal,
比如车祸，或者是被蛇攻击，
like a car crash, or a snake striking,
而其它的是低度兴奋的图像，
while others were lower arousal images
如小兔子和自然场景。
like bunny rabbits and nature scenes.
参与者被要求按一个按钮。
The participants were asked to push a button.
之后他们看到一个空白的电脑屏幕，持续6秒钟。
They then saw a blank computer screen for six seconds.
然后计算机随机选择
The computer then randomly selected
其中一张照片，并显示三秒钟。
one of these photographs that it displayed for three seconds.
之后，屏幕空白10秒,
After that the screen went blank for 10 seconds,
并提示他们再次按下按钮，
and they were prompted to push the button again,
他们重复了该过程大约30次。
and they repeated this protocol about 30 times.
当我们分析所有的数据时，
When we analyzed all the data,
结果令人震惊。
the results were astounding.
在参与者用眼睛看到图像之前，
The heart seemed to know the images
心似乎知道了这些图像。
before the participants ever saw the images with their eyes.
如果将看到的画面是
If the future picture was going to be
情感激昂的图片之一，
one of the emotionally arousing ones,
在图像随机出现在屏幕
the heart rate started to drop about five seconds
之前的五秒钟，
before the image was randomly
心跳开始加速。
selected to be shown on the screen.
而没人知道将会出现什么图片。
So nobody could know what this future picture was going to be.
心跳降幅速度要大得多，
The heart had a much greater de-acceleration
而不是一幅平静的画面。
than if it was, say, going to be a calm picture.
实际上，这些结果后来在全世界
These results have since been replicated
许多不同的独立实验室中得到了验证。
in many different independent labs around the world, actually.
很多人说，我心里无感，
Well, a lot of people say that I don't feel it in my heart,
而在内脏中有感。
I feel it in my gut.
但真正发生的情况是这样的。
But here's what's really happening.
信息先到达心脏。
The information comes to the heart first.
之后心脏会发出不同的信号给大脑，
The heart then sends a different signal
而这些信号我们可以测量得到。
to the brain which we can measure.
然后是你的大脑会有反应再，然后是身体反应。
Then you have a brain response, and then a body response.
随着身体的反应，如肠胃有所感觉，
And with the body response, like feeling in the gut,
或者脖子后面的毛发,
or the hair on the back of the neck,
就是它变得有意识的地方。
is where it becomes conscious.
真正的信息流是心脏、大脑、身体。
But the real flow of information is heart, brain, body.
而这一切都发生在
And this is all happening in many seconds
实际事件发生前的许多秒。
before the actual event occurs.
因此，这些研究告诉我们的是，
So what this body of research is telling us is
心脏似乎与一种不受
that the heart seems to be connected to a type of intuition
时间和空间限制的直觉有关。
that is not bound by the limits of time and space.
但是直觉从何而来呢？
But what is that source of intuition?
心与什么相连，我们怎样才能
What is the heart connected to, and how can we
学会更多地使用它呢？
learn to tap into more of that?
我相信一个与自己的心
I believe that the person who is
脱节的人是没有生命可言的。
disconnected from his or her heart is not living.
我知道很多人都有这种感觉，
I know a lot of people who [? felt ?] that
虽然他们走路、说话、看电视,
but they walk, they talk, they watch television,
有时工作很努力，但心却不在焉。
they work hard sometimes.
我们是地球上唯一可以
We're the only living form on Earth
真正变为行尸走肉的生命形式。
that can actually become the walking dead.
我们实际上可以切断我们自己的活力来源。
We can actually cut off our own source to aliveness.
但不知何故，这种神性能量的火花消失了。
But somehow this spark of divine energy is lost.
这事就曾发生在我身上。
This happened to me.
我说，哦，我想成为一个作家。
I said, oh, I want to be a writer.
我的乐队说，哦，来吧，保罗。
My band says, oh come on, Paulo.
在巴西，要想成为一名作家很难，
In Brazil, to be a writer in Brazil,
没有人能靠写作谋生。
nobody can make a living out of writing.
我说，我不在乎，我只想快乐。
I said, but I don't care, I just want to be happy.
我只是想做点能让我开心的事。
I just want to do something that is going to give me fun.
这会让我的人生有意义。
It's going to give a meaning for my life.
他们说，不，不，不，不，不。
And they said, no, no, no, no, no.
然后，当然，
And then, of course,
因为我觉得老年人更有智慧，
because I thought that old people are wiser,
我说，好吧，他们说的有道理。
I said, OK, they have reason.
让我做点别的事情。
Let me do something different.
但我做不了。
But I could not.
我离开了大学，我只是... ，我说,
I quit the university to I was only ... and I said,
你必须自断后路。
you have to burn your bridges.
我就这样自断后路了。
And I just burned my bridges.
我别无选择，
And I had no choice
只能跟随我想做的事情。
but to follow the thing that I wanted to do.
因此，从我意识到
So from the moment that I realized
想成为作家的那一刻起，我说，我要成为一名作家。
that I want to be a writer, I said, I'm going to be a writer.
这可能需要10天，10年，或20年,
It may take 10 days, 10 years, or 20 years,
但我要写作。
but I'm going to write.
于是，我就从为歌曲写歌词开始，
And then I started by writing lyrics for songs,
我从为报纸写文章开始。
I start by writing articles for newspapers.
我40岁的时候写了第一本书,
I wrote my first book when I was 40,
但至少我写了我的第一本书。
but at least I wrote my first book.
所以最后，如果你不能实现你的梦想,
So at the end, if you don't fulfill your dream,
上帝会找到三四种方式敲打你的头，
God finds three, four times a way to kick your head
然后对你说，来吧。
and say, come on.
不要忘记你人生的使命。
Don't forget your purpose in your life.
给自己的梦想一个机会。
Give a chance to your dream.
你不会后悔的。
You are not going to regret.
我不是说你不会受苦。
I'm not saying that you're not going to suffer.
我不是说你不会有挫败。
I'm not saying that you're not going to be defeated.
我是说你不会后悔的。
I'm saying you're not going to go regret it.
中世纪的女神秘主义者，梅希尔德说得好，
The medieval female mystic, Mechthild,
她说，鱼不会淹死在水里，
beautifully said that a fish cannot drown in water
鸟也不会从天上掉下来。
and a bird cannot fall from the sky.
每种生物都必须找到上天赐予的天赋。
Each creature must find their own God-given element.
对鱼类和鸟类来说，这很容易，它们知道自己的天赋。
And it's easy for fish and birds, they know their element.
但对人类来说，就不那么容易了。
But for human beings it's not so easy.
怀着善意，我们总是挣扎于
With well intention, we always struggle
是否跟随我们的内心、我们的直接经验
whether to follow our heart and our direct experience
以及他人的建议和指导。
and the advice and instruction of others.
无论他们是父母、爱人、朋友，
Whether they be parents, loved ones, friends,
还是我们所处时代的潮流，
trends in whatever age we're born into.
没有什么可以替代我们的心
And there's no substitute for following the aliveness
为我们所带来的活力。
that our heart tunes us to.
很多时候，人们都在寻找理想的伴侣,
Many times people are looking for their ideal partner,
却说找不到。
and they say they can't find them.
他们一直在找啊找啊找啊，
They're looking, and they're looking, and they're looking,
却找不到理想伴侣。
and they can't find them.
如果你的灵魂伴侣没有来敲你的门,
Well if your soulmate is not knocking on your door,
并不是说你不够努力。
it's not that you're not looking hard enough.
如果你想找到
If you want to find someone
能够完全爱你和了解你的伴侣，
that can fully love you and know you,
首先你得了解自己和爱自己。
you have to know and love yourself.
当我们能够给自己这种爱，
When we're able to give ourself this kind of love
这意味着我们现在的样子就足够好了，
which says we're good enough just the way we are,
我们在这个世界上是有原因的，
that we're in this world for a reason,
我们永远不会孤独，
that we're never alone,
这种满足感为与他人
that sense of fulfillment provides a foundation
建立成功的关系提供了基础。
for having a successful relationship with someone else.
一个伟大的老师有如一朵简单的花。
A great teacher this is a simple flower.
花若盛开，蜜蜂自来。
When the flower blossoms, the bee comes.
这朵花不会去寻找蜜蜂。
The flower doesn't go looking for the bee.
这才是心灵真正鲜活起来的方式,
And this is where the heart really comes alive,
因为恋爱关系远比
because relationships are far more challenging
我们在电影中看到的更具挑战性。
than what we see in the movies.
好了，开播吧。
All right, roll it.
我一辈子都爱着你。
I've loved you all my life.
但我们才认识两天。
But we only met two days ago.
那是我生命的开始。
That's when my life began.
一段关系的旅程就是
The journey of a relationship is
一次又一次地寻找真爱。
finding love every time again, and again, and again.
一次又一次的寻找真爱意味着
And to find love again and again means
你会失去它，失去它，再失去它。
you're going to lose it, and lose it, and lose it.
人们常常会问，如果心是如此强大,
Often the question arises that if the heart is so powerful,
为什么人们会感到心碎呢？
why is it so easily broken?
我在地球上的日子让我明白,
And my time on Earth has led me to understand,
因为那是心成长的方式。
because that's how the heart grows.
就像我们运动时，
In the same way that when we exercise
我们的肌肉实际上会酸胀疼痛，
our muscles actually break down
这样它们才能变得更健康更强壮,
so that they can get healthy and grow stronger,
心也是这样运作的。
this is how the heart works.
你必须不断克服重重阻碍,
You have to bring forth obstacles,
这就是婚姻的意义所在。
and that's what a marriage is.
你将面临挑战。
You will be challenged.
一天，一个金发女郎走进了查尔斯的生活。
One day a blonde walked into Charles' life.
她真的漂亮吗？
Was she really pretty?
好吧，我对她撒谎，但玛丽安也看到了她。
Well, I'd lie about her, but Marian saw her, too.
是的，她很漂亮。
Yes, she's very pretty.
有时候你会怀疑你的伴侣,
There'll be times when you doubt your partner,
你怀疑你们的关系，
you doubt your relationship,
你对你的伴侣很生气。
and you're angry with your partner.
你身上没有半点好。
There isn't the slightest bit of good in you.
你害怕接近你的伴侣,
You're afraid to get close to your partner,
你被你的伴侣伤害过。
you've been hurt by your partner.
他有事瞒着我，希尔维。
He's hiding something from me, Sylvie.
发生了一些可怕的事。
Something terrible.
这是旅程的一部分。
This is part of that journey.
在这样心碎的时刻，是痛苦的,
You know, in the moment of such breaking, it's agony,
我们感到绝望。
and we feel desperate.
但是心，只是说，给我更多。
But the heart, the heart just says, give me more.
给我多一点。
Give me more.
当你回到爱中，每次回到爱中,
As you come back to love, each time coming back to love,
寻求宽恕，寻求接纳，
finding forgiveness, finding acceptance,
甚至有时会感谢你的伴侣的不足之处，
even thanking your partner at times for their inadequacies
可以这么说，因为它在你自己身上
so to speak, because it poured forth
倾泻出更大的爱，这就是你成长的方式。
greater love within yourself, that is how you grow.
确实有过一场战斗。
There was a battle, all right.
但我不是与保罗开战，而是与我自己。
But it wasn't Paul I had to fight, but myself.
邦妮会对我说，约翰，
Bonnie will say to me, John,
我不想听你的，
I don't want to listen to you
除非你从心里跟我说话。
until you're talking to me from your heart.
我说，不，我在说话，我说得有道理。
I said, no, I'm talking, I'm making sense.
邦妮说，不。
No.
我想听听你的感受。
I want to hear your feeling.
我想从你的语气中听到你的爱。
I want to hear your love in the tone of your voice.
当你能找到它时，我们可以再次交谈。
And when you can find it, we can talk again.
她给我的信息多么简单明了啊！
What a simple message she gives me.
如果她说我脑子有问题，
Now, it would be a mistake for her
这对她来说是个错误，
to say something's wrong with being in my head,
因为那会让我犯下很大的错误。
because that would make a very important part of me wrong.
但她有时会说
But what she'll say is at times what
我的心是关闭的，当我听起来很刻薄或
my heart is closed, when I sound mean
或者专注于做正确的事时...
or focused on being right...
现在，如果你想告诉我是什么困扰着你，没问题。
Now, if you want to tell me what's troubling you, fine.
如果没有，我累了，很晚了，我想回家睡觉。
If not, I'm tired, it's late, and I want to go home to bed.
她会说，现在，我听不下去了。
She'll say, right now, I can't hear this.
我需要多听听你的心声。
I need to hear a little bit more of your heart.
当你准备好说心里话的时候，
When you're ready to talk from your heart,
我就准备好与你交谈了。
I'm ready to talk with you.
我认为我们这个时代的挑战
I think the challenge in our age
就是保持好关系。
is staying in a relationship.
这并不意味着要继续一段虐待性的关系
And that doesn't mean to stay in abusive relationships
或者没有结果的关系中。
or relationships that don't work.
我发现对我来说，
And I have found for me that
在一段友谊或
the difference often as to whether to stay or go
或爱情关系中是去是留，
in a friendship or a love relationship
往往取决于我的所有身份是否受到欢迎。
hinges on whether all of who I am is welcome.
如果有人要求我放弃自我
If I am asked to leave who I am
或者放弃自我的一部分,
or part of who I am outside,
那么不管我们在这段关系中做了什么,
then no matter what we do in that relationship,
我都不会成长的。
I won't grow.
因为我不能和我的心持有联系。
Because I won't be able to stay connected to my heart.
这就是他们的故事真正开始的地方。
And this is where their story really begins.
告诉你结局会很不公平，因为我们希望
It wouldn't be fair to tell you how it ends, for that, we hope,
这是你想亲自体验的事情。
is something you'll want to experience for yourself.
事情会变得很疯狂，不是吗？
Things can get crazy, no?
很多人，他们失去了孩子，
So many people, they lose their kids
因为其中没有关系，
because there is no relationship,
没有联系。
there is no contact.
这是非常糟糕的，因为没有机会再试一次，
Which is very bad, because no time to try again,
再试一次并找到解决办法。
and to try again, to find a solution.
我有四个孩子。
I have four kids.
他们中的一个正在打桌球。
One of them is playing for [? IX. ?]
大概我更关注这个孩子。
Probably I paid more attention to that.
而最大的那个就没那么受关注了,
And then the oldest one got a little bit less attention,
我不知道，他在某种程度上与我做对。
I don't know, and he was against me in a way.
于是我决定，我必须做点什么。
And I decided, I have to do something.
我必须给自己一个接近他的机会。
I have to give him an opportunity to get closer.
后来，我突然告诉他，来吧。
And then all of a sudden I told him, come on.
拿上包包，我们去希腊吧！
We take the bags and we'll go to Greece, you know.
为了说服他，我说，这可能是我最后一次。
I said, in order to persuade him, it might be my last time.
他说，你为什么这么说？
Why did you say that?
我对他说，当我们登上阿尔卑斯山，我会告诉你。
When we go up on the Alps I will tell you.
我没什么可告诉他的。
I had nothing to tell him.
我这样告诉他，是因为不然他不会来,
I just told him because otherwise he wouldn't come,
我知道他不会来。
and I knew that he wouldn't come.
我们从阿姆斯特丹去了希腊雅典。
We went from Amsterdam, to Athens, Greece.
我成为他的兄弟，成为他的伴侣,
You become his brother, you become his mate,
成了他的朋友。
you become his friend.
这事发生在阿尔卑斯山，那里是零下16度，
This would happen up in the Alps, where it was minus 16
我们都冻僵了，所以我们成了一体。
and we're freezing cold, so we became one.
嘿，你在哪，伙计？
Hey, where are you, man?
爸爸，你在哪？
Dad, where are you?
这里有个小房子，来吧！
This is a little house here, come!
你好？
Hello?
你好。
Hello.
嘿！
Hey!
求你了，让我们今晚和你一起睡吧。
Look at this, please, please let us sleep with you tonight.
不知道你是否允许我和威廉今晚睡在这里，
If you allow me to sleep here tonight, me and Willem,
就一晚上。
just for a night.
天太冷了。
It's so cold.
我爱你。
I love you.
然后我们之间所有的摩擦都消失了，
And then everything went away all this friction
因为我和他的心连在了一起。
because I was in the same team with him.
我喜欢这样，我很高兴这个小错误，
And I love that, and I'm very happy that this little mistake
没有把足够的时间
of mine, which was not dedicating
花在我的大儿子身上...
enough time to my oldest son...
我对拳击一窍不通,
I don't know nothing about boxing,
所以照顾一下你爸爸，好吗？
so be careful with your dad, eh?
现在我们是非常非常好的朋友。
And now that we are really, really good friends.
每个父亲和他的儿子都会有不少摩擦。
Every father has good friction with his son.
而且他们喜欢这种摩擦。
And love it.
你有好孩子，不是吗？
You have good kids, no?
当摩擦来临时，我希望你会喜欢。
I hope you will enjoy when the friction is coming.
否则他就没有性格了。
Otherwise he hasn't got any character.
你没事吧？
You OK?
是啊，伙计。
Yeah, man.
所以当你儿子和你作对时，要非常高兴。
So when your son is against you, be very happy.
好吗？
OK?
9月22日星期天，晚上10点54分左右,
On Sunday, September 22nd, at about 10:54 in the evening,
我们的女儿在从科罗拉多州立大学奇科州立图书馆骑自行车回家时，
our daughter was riding her bicycle home from the CSU Chico
被一个醉酒的司机撞了，
State Library when she was struck by a drunk driver
然后被丢在路边等死。
and left on the side of the road to die.
在和护士的电话交谈中,
In the phone conversation with the nurse,
我们知道她出了车祸,
we knew that she had been in an accident,
但我们不知道任何细节。
but we didn't know any of the details.
说是个酒后驾车的司机，还说是个19岁的孩子。
That it was a drunk driver, and that it was a 19-year-old kid.
她当时正在离学校四个街区远的地方骑车回家。
She was riding four blocks home from school.
她离她的公寓只有半个街区。
She was about a half a block from her apartment.
从她被撞击的地方可以看到她的公寓。
You could see her apartment from where she was hit.
你可以站在桥上，
You could actually stand on the bridge
从那里看她的公寓。
and see her apartment from there.
她差一点就到公寓了。
She was so close.
就是这么近，我已经站在那里很多次了，
That's how close it was, and I've stood there so many times
只是看着那个距离。
and just looked at that distance.
想到短短的距离改变了我们的生活。
Just thought about that short distance has changed our lives.
克里斯蒂娜是你不常
Christina was one of those extraordinary people
遇到的非凡人物之一。
that you don't come across very often.
她喜欢学习。
She studied.
她真的想过如何活出生命。
She really thought about how to live her life.
她不像许多人那样在生活中
She didn't just stumble through life
跌跌撞撞，尤其是在她这个年纪。
the way many people do, especially at her age.
从她体重足以献血开始，她就献血了。
From the time she weighed enough to give blood, she gave it.
有时她甚至会昏倒,
And sometimes she would even pass out,
桑德拉会开车送她回家，对她说,
and Sandra would drive her home in the car, she'd say,
你不能再献血了，不能再这么做了。
that's it, you're not going to do this again.
她说，不，我要再献一次。她献了。
She'd say, no, I am going to do this again and she would.
她一有机会就会献血。
She would give blood whenever she had the chance and..
每次都晕过去。
Pass out every time.
她几乎每次都会晕过去。
And she'd pass out almost every time.
这就是她的生活方式。
That's the way she lived her life.
如果她认为这么做是对的，她就会做。
If she thought it was the right thing to do, she did it.
很多人都知道该做什么,
And so many people know the right thing to do,
但他们并不总是这么做。
but they don't always do it.
但她根本不用考虑。
But she didn't even have to think about it.
克里斯蒂娜去世后三周左右,
About three weeks after Christina died,
我们得去收拾她在奇科的公寓。
we had to go and pack up her apartment up in Chico.
我打开抽屉，看到一个化妆包。
And I opened up a drawer and I saw a makeup bag.
我打开了化妆包，
I opened up the makeup bag
看到里面有几张纸。
and it had several pieces of paper in it.
里面没有化妆品，只有几张纸。
No makeup, but several pieces of paper.
在那些纸中有一张纸，
And among those papers was this piece of paper
是折叠起来的，有点破旧。
that was folded and a little tattered.
我看着它，开始阅读。
And I looked at it and I started to read.
我认出这是遗愿清单。
And I realized it was bucket list.
她从没说过想发财，或想出名。
She never said I want to be rich, I want to be famous.
她没有提出任何不合理的要求。
She didn't ask for anything unreasonable.
她只想做些正常的事，
She just wanted to do normal stuff
而从来没有机会这么做。
and she never got to do that.
同时出现在四个地方。
Be in four places at once.
有个地方叫四角。
There's a place called Four Corners.
你实际上可以来到四个州边缘处，
You can actually go to the edge of all four states,
那是她想做的事。
that's what she wanted to do.
但她已经这么做了。
But she's done this already.
不是因为她在场，而是因为她的器官。
Not by being there, but with her organs.
她的器官捐给了四个人，而这四个人到了这四个地方。
Parts of her are four places at once.
她的肝脏切割后捐给了两个人。
Her liver was split between two people.
其中一个是55岁的男人，另一个是9个月大的婴儿。
One was a 55-year-old man and one was a nine-month-old baby.
一个肾脏，捐给了一个他们家认识的人。
A kidney, somebody that the family knew.
另一个人得到了克里斯蒂娜剩下的肝脏。
Another man got the rest of Christina's liver.
她的胰腺和另一个肾
Her pancreas and the other kidney
捐给了一个住在南湾的男人。
went to a man in the South Bay.
她的心脏捐给了一个来自斯坦福大学
And her heart went to a 64-year-old woman
住在南湾的64岁的女人。
from the South Bay at Stanford.
老子说我只有三样东西教导：
Lao Tzu said that I have just three things to teach：
简单、耐心和慈悲心。
simplicity, patience, and compassion.
在一个我们逃避内心
In an age where we run from the depth of feeling
深处的感受和教导的时代，
and the teachings of the heart,
我们的恐惧会重新定义简单为愚蠢,
our fear can reframe simplicity as stupidity,
耐心为懒惰，慈悲为多愁善感。
patience as laziness, and compassion as sentimentality.
因此，觉得它们不值得实践。
And therefore make them not worthwhile to pick up.
简单意指直接体验生活，获得第一手的经验。
Simplicity refers to direct living, firsthand experience.
回归到直接触碰生活。
So the return to touching life directly.
这可以恢复我们的身心完整。
This restores our wholeheartedness.
耐心也使我们恢复身心完整。
Patience also restores us to wholeheartedness.
我们一直感到的紧迫感大多是虚假的。
The urgencies we feel ever present are mostly false.
除非你我不能呼吸或者在流血,
Unless you or I can't breathe or we're bleeding,
其实没什么大不了的。
there's no real urgency.
慈悲，从字面上来说，
And compassion, compassion literally
意指真诚地与人相处。
means to be with, to keep honest company.
因此，当我没有直接体验生活时，当我没有耐心时,
So when I am not directly living, when I am not patient,
我想解决你的痛苦，
I want to problem solve your pain
而不是陪着你。
and not keep you company with it.
经常有人问我，道理上都说得通，
I'm often asked, well that's fine,
但是在现实世界中我们怎么才能做到呢？
but how can we do that in the real world?
我不这么认为。
And I see it differently.
我开始明白如果你不敞开心扉,
I've come to understand that if you don't open your heart,
那么现实就会碾压你。
then existence will crush you.
不是因为存在有什么邪恶的东西，
Not because there's something evil about existence,
就像水可以填满一个洞，
but because the way water fills a hole,
如果你不以你自己的身份去迎接这个世界，
if you don't meet the world with who you are then
那么周围的一切就会把你填满。
everything around will just fill you in.
所以总有一个问题，是的，如果我在外面的世界,
So there's always a question, yes, if I'm out in the world,
我可能会受伤，可能会被人利用。
I could get hurt, I could get taken advantage of.
我可能会被人背叛。
I could get betrayed.
我的信任可能得不到回报。
My trust may not be rewarded.
这些都是真的。
This is all true.
但我发现，不保持敞开心扉、
But I have found that the cost for not staying
全心全意的代价是，
open hearted, whole hearted, is that
我失去了对自己生命力的接触。
I lose access to my aliveness.
我们最终将步入一个
And we'll end up walking lock step
消费主义、获取、恐惧和担忧的社会。
in a society of consumerism, of getting, of fear, and of worry.
我们不会活出自己的人生。
And we will not have lived our life.
我们要过自己的人生。
We have a life to live.
我们的心有答案。
The heart has the answers.
我是一家杂志的编辑，一年前就职。
I was editor of a magazine, I started that one years ago.
我在看这本杂志。
And I was looking at this magazine.
和往常一样，
And as usual, there was this picture
杂志前还有这张编辑的照片。
of the editor in front of the magazine.
我看着自己，微笑着，我想,
And I was looking at myself smiling, and I thought,
这不是真的。
it's not true.
这不是我。
This is not me.
但是有一种悲伤，就像一股
But there was a sadness, it was like a wave
悲伤的浪潮冲刷着我。
of sadness that washed me.
那一刻我真的很难过。
It was a really upset moment.
我现在可以笑了。
I can laugh at it now.
我想，这个我，或自我是谁？
And I thought, who is this me, or I, or self?
在宗教或灵性传统,
What is it in religion, or in spiritual traditions,
或哲学中，我是什么？
or in philosophy?
它是什么？
What is it?
历史上所有的灵性传统
Every spiritual tradition throughout history
都将心视为灵魂的种子。
has spoken about the heart as being the seed of the soul.
心中的金刚，心中的莲花，
The diamond in the heart, the lotus and the heart,
心中的殿堂。
the temple in the heart.
每个传统都讲心
Every tradition speaks about the heart
是我们的本质。
as being the essence of who we are.
心指向你内在最重要的维度。
The heart points to the most essential dimension within you.
活在这种联系中,
So to live in connectedness with that,
那么你就接触到了心灵的力量
then you are in touch with the power of the heart, which
它也是生命本身的力量。
is the power of life itself.
智慧的力量遍及整个宇宙，
The power of the very intelligence
并奠定了整个宇宙的基础。
that pervades and underlies the entire universe.
神圣的智慧在你的心中。
Divine intelligence is in your heart.
你不会在你的智力中找到你的灵魂。
You will not find your soul in your intellect.
我突然想到，哇，看看这些笔记。
And I suddenly thought, wow, look at all these notes.
这可能是一本杂志。
This could be a magazine.
标题很简单，因为它让我很开心。
And the title was easy, because it made me really happy.
感到很幸福。
Happiness.
倾听自己的内心可能非常可怕的,
So to listen to your heart can be very frightening,
因为你可能会失去所有
because you might have to lose all the secure things that
生活给你的安全的东西，比如车、钱、房子和一切东西。
life was giving you, like cars, money, houses, everything.
我是个非常害怕的人。
Well, I'm a person who has a lot of fear.
比如说，每次我
Like for example, every time that I
不得不写一本新书。
have to write a new book.
我会担心我能充分表达自己吗？
Would I be able to express myself?
我能分享我的灵魂吗？
Would I be able to share my soul?
当我们考虑挑战恐惧时,
When we consider challenging fear,
我们实际上是在考虑将觉照之光
we're actually considering shining the light of awareness
照射到我们内心那些恐惧的地方。
on those places within us that are fearful.
恐惧并没有什么错。
There is nothing wrong with fear.
唯一错误的就是被恐惧所麻痹。
The only thing that is wrong is to be paralyzed by fear.
所以我想，好吧，我面对这种恐惧，我只是面对它。
So I thought, OK, I face it, I just face it, this fear.
如果这本杂志不成功，我会怎么样？
What will happen to me if this magazine is not a success?
也许我得把房子卖了。
Maybe I have to sell the house.
所以我找了另一栋房子。
So I looked to another house.
在村子里你可以租到很便宜的房子住。
An area in the village where you can rent a very cheap house.
我想，我能住在那里吗？
I thought, can I live there?
我当然可以住在那里。
Of course I can live there.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
有屋顶，有房间，我可以住在那里。
It's a roof, it's a house, I can live there.
我知道我能处理好。
And I knew I can handle this.
不管发生什么，我们都会活下去。
Whatever will happen, we will live.
苏族有句老话，
And there's an old Sioux saying
也就是说，你一生中最长的旅程，
that says, the longest journey you will make in your life
是从你的头到你的心。
is from your head to your heart.
这不是因为我们愚蠢或者迟钝。
And this isn't because we're stupid or we're slow.
因为这需要时间。
It's because it takes time.
在我得癌症之前，我相信心，
Before I had cancer, I believed in the heart
但我活在脑中。
but I was living it from my head.
那段旅程，就像融入地下的雪,
And that journey, like snow melting into the ground,
我生命的精华融入了我的心。
the essence of my life melted into my heart.
我几乎是死里逃生，才完成了
It took almost dying to make that journey
从脑到心的这段旅程。
from my head to my heart.
你的初衷应该是
Your primary intention needs to be
此时此刻与心的联系。
connectedness with the heart at this moment.
我必须出于好意才行动。
I have to act from a place of good intention.
从一个充满爱和仁慈的地方开始，
A place of love and kindness that
会让我行走在这个世界上
will allow me to walk in this world
而不造成任何损害。
without creating any damage.
你可能想要一百万美元,
You may intend to have a million dollars,
达成这个目的可能就需要你去抢银行。
and that intention then needs you to rob a bank.
如果你真的想要这个东西，你可以直面内心，说,
If you really want the thing, go to the heart and say,
这就是我想要的。
this is what I want.
心会说，我会告诉你如何得到它。
And the heart can say, I'll show you how you get it.
你现在必须愿意去工作，相信我。
You must be willing to work, now, and trust me, now.
然后你就可以拥有它了，是的。
And then you can have it, yes.
如果不会伤害到其他人的话。
If it's not going to hurt anyone else.
假设你遇到一个人说,
Suppose you meet someone who says,
我打算赚更多的钱。
I intend to make more money.
他说，这就是我的意图。
And he says, that's my intention.
你可以问他，为什么你想赚更多的钱？
You can ask him, why do you want to make more money?
然后你会开始了解到一些有趣的东西。
And then you'll start to learn some interesting things.
如果赚钱成为你的首要目标,
If making money becomes your primary goal,
那么要知道你与你自己
then know that you are not connected
最深处的维度没有联结，
with the deepest dimension in yourself
我们称之为心。
that we call the heart.
即使你实现了目标，赚了很多钱,
And even if you achieve your goal and make a lot of money,
你会发现它最终会导致
you will find that ultimately it leads
沮丧和不幸。
to frustration and unhappiness.
实现你的梦想，钱肯定会来。
Fulfill your dream, and certainly money may come.
如果钱不来，能过上快乐的生活也非常好。
If money does not come, just to have a life full of joy.
以我为例，我从没想过
In my case, for example, I never thought
我会以写作为生。
I would make a living out of writing.
我写作是因为我想写作。
I was writing because I wanted to do it.
我别无选择。
I had no choice.
所以到最后，
So at the end of the day,
我不仅靠写作赚钱，
not only I made money out of writing,
而且我靠写作赚了很多钱。
but I made a lot of money out of writing.
经常发生的情况是，当你的行动变得有能力
It often happens that when your actions become empowered
并为这个世界做出了重要贡献时，
and contribute something vital to this world,
然后某种形式的富足，
then abundance in some form and
可能是以金钱的形式，
it may be in the form of money,
有时就会流向你。
can sometimes flow to you.
这是一个巨大的成功。
It was a great success.
荷兰希望这本杂志能够发展壮大，
Holland wanted this magazine so it could grow,
它是荷兰最大的杂志。
and it was the biggest magazine of the Netherlands.
这是发自内心的。
It came from the heart.
是真的。
It was the real thing.
无论你的心在哪里，你都会找到你的宝藏。
Wherever your heart is, there you will find your treasure.
心就是你。
The heart is who you are.
心定义了你。
The heart defines you.
我真的很想见见那个人,
And I really wanted to meet that person,
因为我知道那个人必须非常特别
because I knew that person had to be pretty special
才能得到克里斯蒂娜的心脏。
to get Christina's heart.
一天深夜，我儿子收到一个朋友发来的短信,
Late one evening, my son got a text message from a friend,
说，让你妈妈看看脸书主页。
and said, tell your mom to read the Facebook page.
于是我登陆脸书网站，看到了一条信息。
So I went to Facebook, and I saw a message.
这条信息是，我是苏珊·维埃拉,
And the message was, I am Susan Vieira,
我相信我是你女儿心脏的接受者。
and I believe I'm the recipient of your daughter's heart.
我知道时间很晚了，但我还是想给她发个短信。
I knew it was late, but I just figured I'd message her anyway.
她收到短信后马上回应了。
And she responded right back.
我拨了她的号码，她接了。
And I dialed her number, and she picked up.
我立刻感觉到了一种联系。
And right away I just felt a connection.
我感觉到了克里斯蒂娜。
I felt Christina.
后来我听说她是个退休护士,
And then when I heard this she was a retired nurse,
她们有很多共同点,
and that they had so much in common,
就像克里斯蒂娜亲手挑选了苏珊
that it was like Christina handpicked Susan
来得到她的心脏一样。
to get her heart.
克里斯蒂娜和我都是护士。
Christina and I were both nurses.
我看到了遗愿清单，那真的是我人生的一份简历。
I saw the bucket list, and it's really a CV of my life.
她想管理和拥有自己的企业。
She wanted to manage and own her own business.
是的，我做到了。
Yes, I did that.
她想结婚。
She wanted to get married.
是的，我做到了。
Yes, I've done that.
她想学开飞机。
She wanted to learn how to fly a plane.
我学会了开飞机。
I've learned to fly a plane.
她想去世界七大
She wanted to go to four out of seven
奇迹中的四个所在地。
of the wonders of the world.
是的，完成。
Yes, check.
在飞机上坐头等舱。
Fly first class on an airplane.
完成。
Check.
拜访50个州。
Visit the 50 states.
我正在努力。
I'm working on it.
乘坐热气球。
Ride in a hot air balloon.
我做到了。
I've done that.
去跳伞。
Go parachuting.
这项清单我得再等等。
I'm going to have to wait a while on that one.
骑骆驼。
Ride a camel.
做到了。
Done that.
去所有的大陆旅行。
Travel to all the continents.
正在进行中。
Working on it.
作为笑脸女孩而被铭记。
Be remembered as the smiley girl.
这项清单我仍在进行中。
I'm still working on that one, too.
她想救别人的命,
She wanted save someone's life,
她在死的时候做到了这一点。
which she did that in death.
她想拥有两处房产，其中一处养牲畜。
She wanted to own two pieces of property, one with livestock.
我犹豫了这项清单。
I hesitated on that one.
我拥有两处房产,
I've owned two pieces of property,
但并没有养牲畜。
but they didn't have livestock on them.
去阻止两个为她打架的男人。
She went to break up a fight between two guys over her.
不，我还没做过那个。
No, I haven't done that one.
穿过一片罂粟田。
She wanted to run through a poppy field.
我也没有实现这项清单。
I haven't done that, either.
游览尼亚加拉大瀑布。
Tour Niagara Falls.
我想去尼亚加拉大瀑布。
I'd love to go to Niagara Falls.
生孩子。
And have children.
我不这么认为。
I don't think so.
这是一个
At this point, that's one I'm not
我完成不了的遗愿清单。
going to accomplish on her bucket list.
前往史密森尼博物馆并沿 66 号公路行驶。
Go to the Smithsonian and drive along Route 66.
从加州一路开到田纳西州。
Drove it all the way from California to Tennessee.
完成这些对她来说非常重要，
And it was so important to her that these
以至于我们知道这是我们想做的事情。
get done that we knew it was something that we wanted to do.
我也制定了目标，那就是尽可能多地去尝试和
I also made the goal to try and do as many
完成遗愿清单上未完成的项目。
of the undone items on the bucket list.
进行心脏移植手术，
Having a heart transplant,
有些事情她做不到。
there's things that she can't do.
她不能跳伞，
She can't go skydiving or parachuting,
所以我们会替她做。
so we'll do that for her.
我跳不了伞，因为我太害怕了，但会完成它的。
It won't be me because I'm too scared, but it'll get done.
清单上我们能做的一切，我们都会做。
Everything on that list that we can do, we'll do.
当你被打败的时候，
When are defeated,
你不能假装你在精神上是优越的。
you cannot pretend that you are spiritually superior.
坐下来，哭泣，忍受，说，哦，我的上帝,
Sit down, and cry, and suffer, and say, oh my God,
你为什么抛弃我？
why did you forsake me?
你可以哭。
You are allowed to cry.
你可以被打败。
You are allowed to be defeated.
如何不否认我的痛苦，因为如果我们否认它,
How not to deny my pain, because if we deny it,
它会变得更大。
it will get bigger.
如何不被淹没在其中呢？
And how not to drown in it.
当我们痛苦的时候，我们被呼求让美进来。
We are asked to let in beauty while we're suffering.
我听到了。
I hear it.
我记得她小时候，
I remember when she was little,
他们会把我的头靠在她的胸前，
and they would lay my head on her chest,
我会听到她的心声。
and I would hear her heart.
这就是我今天的感受。
That's how I felt today.
我想这就是我多次听到的心声。
I thought that's the heart I heard so many times.
很好。
Good.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
别客气。
You're welcome.
我经历了失去女儿的痛苦
I went through the experience of losing my daughter
因为医院存在渎职和疏忽,
because there was malpractice and negligence in the hospital,
我女儿变成了植物人，真的。
and my daughter became a vegetable, really.
昏迷了一年直到她最终死去。
In a coma for a year until she finally was liberated and died.
我可以在余生中承担对
And I could carry for the rest of my life
所发生的事情的愤怒和怨恨的负担。
the burden of the anger and resentment of what happened.
我可以指责并起诉医院。
I could blame and sue the hospital.
但我选择了写书。
But I chose to write a book instead.
在那本书里，我瞥见了整个过程。
And in that book I sort of glimpsed the whole thing.
我明白发生了什么事。
I understood what had happened.
我意识到其中没有恶意。
I realized that there was no bad intention.
有无知，有疏忽，
There was ignorance, negligence,
但并没有伤害她的目的存于其中。
but not the purpose of harming her.
我宽恕了这件事，我已经能够
And I forgave, and I've been able to live
带着我女儿快乐的精神生活了19年。
for 19 years with the spirit of my daughter happily.
我不背负这个负担。
I don't carry that burden with me.
每当我难以宽恕时,
Whenever I'm having a difficult time forgiving,
我想到了伊利·巴吉萨。
I think of Immaculee Ilibagiza.
我在家待了... 一天。
I was home for ... Day.
我兄弟来到我的房间
My brother come to my room--
你还在睡觉吗？
You're still sleeping?
他看起来好像醒了好几个小时。
He looked like he was awake for many hours.
你不知道发生了什么吗？
You don't know what happened?
我从床上跳下来，我从来没有
I jumped out of the bed, I never did this
在我哥哥面前这么做过，我穿上我的衣服。
before in front of my brother, put on my clothes.
我们会赢的！
We will win!
找蟑螂！（对恶语）
Find the cockroaches!
找蟑螂！
他说,
He said,
我们国家的总统昨晚去世了。
The president of our country died last night.
他们会杀了我们的。
They're going to kill us.
我来自一个图西族部落。
I come from a tribe of Tutsi.
我们部落很受欢迎。
It was well-loved.
我们有点怀疑会发生什么事。
And we kind of suspected something might happen.
我父母让我躲在一个邻居家
My parents sent me to hide to a neighbor,
他是胡图族人。
who was from the Hutu tribe.
他是位新教牧师，
It was a protestant pastor, and he
他让我和其他七名妇女
put me to sleep in a bathroom of three
睡在三乘四英尺的浴室里。
by four feet with other seven women.
我们不能谈话，不能说话，就像那个人告诉我们的那样,
We couldn't talk, we couldn't speak, as the man told us,
我甚至不会告诉我的孩子们。
I won't even tell my children.
一个错误，一个错误。
One mistake, one mistake.
不是我不信任我的孩子,
It's not that I don't trust my children,
但这个错误，对你们来说已经太迟了，
but this mistake, it would be too late for you
你们的人生就完了。
and your life will be over.
别用淋浴器。
Don't use the shower.
仅当有人在隔壁浴室
Only flush the water of the bathroom
冲水时才冲水。
when someone is flushing the water in the next bathroom.
我认为我们需要待上一周，
I think [? that we'll be in for ?] a
也许更短的时间。
week or maybe less.
如果我们小心点，我们也许能挺过去。
But if we are careful, we might live through this.
大家小心点。
Just be careful.
我们原只待两三天。
We thought it was going to be two, three days.
我们后来在那间浴室里待了三个月。
We spent in that bathroom three months.
你不能放松警惕。
You must not let your guard down.
图西族份子东躲西藏,
The Tutsi snakes are hiding in the grass,
所以要确保你...
so make sure that you have your [INAUDIBLE]
把他们劈成两半。
ready to chop the snakes in half.
我们不能洗澡。
We couldn't shower.
我们每天都在等刽子手来找我们。
We were waiting for killers to find us every day.
如果你在田间工作，
If you're working a field and
发现灌木丛中有在哺乳的图西族妇女,
spot a Tutsi woman in the bushes breastfeeding her baby,
不要浪费这个千载难逢的机会。
don't waste a golden opportunity.
拿起你的枪，射击他们，把他们劈成两半
Pick up your gun, shoot them, chop the snakes in half.
别忘了杀了孩子。
Don't forget to kill the baby.
斩草除根。
The child of a snake is a snake.
他们挨家挨户地搜查,
They went home by home to search,
看看有没有人躲起来。
to see if anyone was hiding.
这是一个由政府雇佣的组织，
And this was a group that was paid by the government,
给他们提供食物、饮料和烟。
given food, and drink, smokes.
他们第一次来的时候，我记得我在看,
The first time they came, I remember I was watching,
我透过浴室的小窗户看到了他们。
and I saw them through the tiny window of the bathroom.
男人们围着房子转，
The men circled the house
以免有人从窗户跳出来，
so that no one jumps out of the window
然后他们开始喊叫。
and then they started to scream.
他们进了每个房间，钻到了床底下,
They went in every room, they went under the beds,
他们甚至打开行李箱，
they even opened suitcases
以确保没有婴儿藏在里面。
to make sure there was no babies hiding.
他们打着手电筒进入房子的天花板，
They went in the ceiling of the house with flashlights
确保没人躲在天花板里。
to make sure no one is hiding in the ceiling.
他们还会去屋顶，
They went on the roof of the house
确保没人躲在那里。
to make sure no one is laying there.
我记得我问，如果你在那里，可以控制这一切,
I remember asking, if you are there, can control all this,
千万别让他们发现浴室的门。
please don't let them find the door of the bathroom.
就像千根针刺进你的身体。
A thousand needles went through your body.
很痛苦。
It was painful.
那不是一点点恐惧，而是很多很多。
It wasn't a little fear, it was a lot.
感觉人生就要结束了。
Your life was about to be over.
你即将被砍刀砍死
You are about to be cut by machetes.
图西族人呢？
Where are the Tutsis?
不，不，不，我不知道你在说什么。
No, no, no, don't know what you're talking about.
我是个胡图族良民。
I'm a good Hutu.
我绝不会把图西族人藏起来，这里没有图西族人。
I would never hide Tutsis, there are no Tutsis here.
我不想和政府有任何矛盾。
I don't want any problem with the government.
你了解我的，我会保护这个家的。
You know me, I shall protect this house.
那些图西族叛军进来攻击我
First those Tutsi rebels come in and attack me
因为我是个好胡图族人。
for being such a good Hutu.
他们直接来到浴室门口。
They came right to the door of the bathroom.
其中一个碰了把手。
One of them touched the handle.
他告诉那个人。
He told the man.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我相信你。
I trust you.
你是个好人。
You are a good man.
哦，谢谢。
Oh, thank you.
你现在是我们的一员了。
You are one of us now.
我是说，当看到他时，我们跳了起来。
I mean, when we saw him, we jumped.
我们以为是凶手在找我们。
We thought it was the killers finding us.
你们现在安全了。
You're safe now.
你们能活下来已经很幸运了。
You're lucky to be alive.
头五个小时我们完全麻木了。
We were completely numb for the first five hours.
我不知道你们是怎么祈祷的,
I don't know how you are praying,
也不知道你们是否在祈祷。
or if you're even praying.
但不管你们在做什么，请坚持下去。
But whatever you're doing, please keep doing it.
我在浴室里的感觉
You know, the feelings I had in that bathroom
是我一生中从未经历过的事情。
were things I never experienced in my life.
我很生气，无法用言语表达。
I had anger, anger I cannot put in words.
我的意思是，有时候人们讨厌一个人,
I mean, sometimes people hate one person,
就已经够糟了。
and that's bad enough.
而我讨厌八百万人。
I hated like eight million people.
我记得我当时想，当我出来的时候,
And I remember thinking, when I got out,
我要成为一名战士，
I'm going to be a soldier,
我会训练身体和肌肉，
and I will train my body and muscles,
然后杀了所有胡图族人。
and just kill everybody.
在愤怒时，我就是兰博（电影第一滴血主角，由史泰龙扮演）。
In my anger, I was Rambo.
在我看过的一些电影里，我感觉自己在杀人。
In some movies I have seen, I was killing people.
带着这些想法，我会出于愤怒而发誓。
With these thoughts I would be swearing out of anger.
我坐在浴室里带着这些想法,
And I'm sitting in the bathroom with these thoughts,
我的头很痛，我的胃也很痛。
my head would be aching, and my stomach is aching.
为什么我的念头会激起这种毒素？
Why my thoughts are provoking this poison?
我只是在想我想做的事。
I'm only thinking of things I want to do.
我的想法是怎么回事？
What is going on with my thoughts here?
当我们害怕的时候，很难记住爱。
It's very hard to remember love when we are scared.
恐惧是世界上
Being afraid is one of the strongest
最强大的的情感之一。
emotions in the world.
我们的心率随着每次心跳而变化。
Our heart rate varies with each and every heartbeat.
当我们沮丧、焦虑和情绪低落时,
And when we're frustrated and anxious and emotionally upset,
心脏的节奏变得非常不连贯和参差不齐。
the rhythm of the heart becomes very incoherent and jagged.
这基本上会在人体系统中产生一种噪音，
And this basically creates a noise in the system
淹没了直觉信号。
that drowns out the intuitive signals.
我记得当时在想，这房子有两个浴室。
I remember thinking, this home has two bathrooms.
如果他们没有这两个浴室,
If they didn't have these two bathrooms,
我们怎么可能藏在里面？
how could we have been hidden here?
他们会找到我们的。
They would have find us.
只有房子里有两个浴室,
It was only home that had two bathrooms inside the house,
这让我感觉很好。
and that made me feel good.
当我想到好的方面时，
When I was thinking the good,
它是如此与众不同，
it was so distinctive
因为你的感情是如此之嗨，
because the feelings were so high
以至于你能感觉到不同，
you can feel the difference
就像有人推着你并把你举起来。
like someone just pushed you down and lifted you up.
好像很清明似的。
Like it's so clearly.
然后我开始想，我们可以吃东西了。
And I started thinking, we can eat.
感谢上帝，这个人有孩子。
Thank God this man has children.
我们可以吃剩菜，即使不是很多。
We can eat the leftovers, even if it was not much.
所以我开始去看好的一面，
So I started to see the good,
好像我的心是敞开的。
and it was like my heart was open.
看着这些人，我能触碰到他们。
Look at these people, I can touch somebody.
只是为了看到一切的美好。
Just to see the good in everything.
欣赏是一种与心灵相关的感觉。
Appreciation is a heart related feeling.
它需要使用心灵的智慧
It requires access to the intelligence
去欣赏或感恩。
of the heart to appreciate, or to have gratitude.
当我这么想的时候，我觉得自己明智多了。
And when I was thinking that way, I felt much smarter.
当我们处于一致状态时,
When we're in a coherent state,
从心脏到大脑的信号要强烈得多。
the signal from the heart to the brain is so much stronger.
到达我们的额叶皮层时就更清晰了。
It gets up to our frontal cortex much clearer.
那是心在敲你的门,
That's the heart knocking on your door,
说，打开门，我就在这里。
saying, open the door, here I am.
你需要我。
You need me.
因为你会说，哦，我在哪里？
Because then you say, ooh, where am I?
我在地狱。
I'm in hell.
我不知道。
I didn't know that.
但是心告诉你，相信我。
But the heart tells you, trust me.
当你出来的时候...
And when you're out of that...
它开始非常非常迅速地转移能量，
It begins to shift the energies very, very quickly
这样你就进入了超越问题的
so that you come into another level of buoyancy that
另一个层次的空间。
rises above the problem.
这样一来，你就可以看透它。
And in doing so, you can then see into it.
然后你就可以找到解决问题的方法。
You can then find ways to deal with it.
他们回来了。
They're coming back.
我心里很清楚。
It was so clear in my heart.
这次他们想找到你。
This time they want to find you.
牧师。
Pastor.
把衣柜推到门前。
Push the wardrobe in front of the door.
他们不会发现有门的。
They're not going to see there is a door.
不，不，为什么？
No, no, why?
如果他们来了，就会发现不在这里。
If they come, they'll realize it wasn't here.
求你了。
I'm begging you.
好的。
OK.
好吧，好吧，我会把柜子推过去。
OK, OK, I will put it.
很明显我需要倾听这个直觉。
And it was so clear that I need to listen to that.
他们来搜查了。
They came to search.
她在哪，牧师？
Where is she, Pastor?
这是她最后出现的地方。
This is the last place she was seen.
我们知道她在这里。
We know she's here.
伊玛库莱！
Immaculée!
其中一个说，我杀了399只蟑螂。
One of them said, I've killed 399 cockroaches.
一些胡图族民族主义者称呼图西族人为蟑螂
他说，我希望伊玛库莱是第400个。
And he said, I want Immaculee to be the 400th.
我在想，这个人，我认识他。
And I'm thinking, this man, I knew him.
他是我的小学同学。
He was a school mate in elementary school.
一个我可以称之为朋友的人。
Someone I can call a friend.
怎么会有人说他用弯刀杀了399个图西人,
How can somebody say he killed 399 people by machete,
而且他还很骄傲呢？！
but he was proud?
他们打开了衣柜。
They went right in the wardrobe.
如果没有那个衣柜，他们本可以找到我们的。
They could have find us if that wardrobe was not there.
后来他说，好主意。
And later he said, good idea.
我甚至都不想邀功,
It wasn't even like I wanted to take credit,
比如说，哦，太好了，我有个好主意。
like oh good, I had a good idea.
就好像，继续倾听心声。
It was just like, keep listening.
知道如何分辨那不被仇恨、羡慕、嫉妒和
Know how to distinguish that clarity that is not covered
任何不爱的东西所覆盖的那份清明。
by hate, by envy, by jealousy, by anything unloving.
这就是它真正的出现方式。
That is really how it comes out.
这是一个事实，
It comes as a truth that you know
不是被不好的东西驱使的。
is not motivated by something not nice.
有趣的是，他们离开时,
And the funny part, when they left,
我的愤怒又回来了。
the anger came right back.
就像沉入水底的石油
It was just like a ... oil coming back
又浮出水面，就像我拉开了面前的面纱。
on the top of the water, like a veil I pulled in front.
我无法说话，无法思考。
I couldn't say, I couldn't think.
哦，我的身体又开始疼了，头也痛了。。
Oh, my body's aching again, and my headache.
当有人在杀你的同胞时，你就会这么做的。
But that's what you do when people are killing your people.
你会生气。
You get angry.
我甚至没有想到
So I didn't even think
还有别的办法来处理这个问题
there was another way to deal with this.
尽管我为自己的身体付出了代价,
Despite the price I was paying with my own body,
我不记得怎样因愤怒而微笑。
I couldn't remember how to smile cause of anger.
我觉得我的嘴巴扭曲了。
I felt like my mouth was twisted.
我希望再次成为无辜之人。
I wished to be innocent again.
我希望看到人们善良的一面。
I wished to see good in people.
但对我来说，他们是动物。
But for me, they were animals.
他们很坏。
They were bad.
他们是些邪恶的人。
They were just evil people.
每天我都要祷告200次我们的主祷文。
Every day I prayed about 200 our Lord's Prayer.
每次我读到这句话的时候，即：
Any time I reached the part that said,
“宽恕我们的罪过，
forgive us our trespasses
正如我们宽恕那些侵犯我们的人一样“，
as we forgive those who trespass against us,
我说不出这句话。
I couldn't say it.
请赐给我们今天的食物。
Give us this day our daily bread.
我宽恕...
Forgive...
每次我经历这种情况，
Any time I went through that part
就像遇到危险信号。
it was like a red flag.
然后我说，我该怎么办？
And then I said, how can I deal with it?
因为我无法宽恕，因为这是不可宽恕的事。
Because I can't forgive, because this is unforgivable thing.
他们想杀了我。
They tried to kill me.
你怎么能宽恕这种事？
How do you forgive such a thing?
我希望我可以，但是在这种情况下，行不通啊！
I wished I could, but it didn't make sense in my situation.
有一次我说，等等，我有个更好的主意。
So one time I said, wait a minute, I have a better idea.
我想，让我跳过这部分的祈祷。
I thought, let me skip that part of the prayer.
那我就不用说了，这样剩下的，我就可以说了。
So then I don't have to say it, then I can say the rest.
我内心认为，上帝知晓一切，祂知道我没有说谎。
So then within me, God is OK, now he knows I'm not lying.
谎言是不会长久的。
Lies don't sit well in the body.
我开始跳过这部分祷文，我感觉好多了。
And I start to skip it, and I felt so much better.
我修改了祷文，之后我听到有个声音，说，
So I edited it, and now this voice says--
你在修改祂的祷告。
You are editing His prayer.
如果我是你，我不会试图修改祂的祷告。
If I were you, I wouldn't try to edit his prayer.
我今天可以这么说笑，
You know, I can say this laughing today,
但那时我的心情很糟糕。
but that time my mood was crushed.
我记得这就像是放弃，
I remember it was like giving up,
或者我可以称之为臣服？
or can I call it surrender?
我跪下来，举起双手，祈求上帝。
I went to my knees, and I put my hands up, and I begged God.
我要把那句话放回祈祷文中。
I'm going to put it back in prayer.
因为如果你这样祈祷，
Because if you said pray this way,
你一定知道这样做是对的。
you must know it is the right thing to do.
我把它交到你手里。
I'm putting it in your hands.
如果你知道如何宽恕，那就帮帮我。
If you know how to forgive, help me out.
我很愿意。
I am willing.
那真是个一个很大的转变。
That was a big shift.
我记得他们来到了一个点，
I remember they came to a point
就像世界被分成了两部分。
when it was like the world was divided in two parts.
一部分是爱，一部分是恨。
A part of love, and a part of hate.
在爱的部分是像曼德拉、
In the part of love are people like Mandela,
特蕾莎修女和甘地这样的人。
like Mother Teresa, Gandhi.
他们是自愿受苦的人。
People who suffered.
不管他们遭受了多少痛苦,
And no matter how much they suffered,
他们仍然坚持真理。
they still stand up for truth.
他们仍然为爱而战，
They still stand up for love,
为捍卫另一个人的权利而站出来。
for defense of another human being's rights.
在仇恨的一面，
And then on the side of hate,
我看到像希特勒这样的人,
I see people like Hitler,
那些在卢旺达制造种族灭绝的人，
like those who were causing genocide in Rwanda
他们报复心很强，易怒，就像当时的我一样。
who are vengeful, angry, like me at that time.
我感觉上帝在问我，
And I felt like God was asking me,
你想站在哪一边？
where do you want to stand?
你想属于哪里？
Where do you want to belong?
你想属于爱的一边还是恨的一边？
Do you want to belong to side of love or the side of hate?
你猜怎么着？
And guess what?
属于爱的一方的人，
People who belong on the side of love,
他们知道不公正，
they have known injustice,
他们知道仇恨，
they have known hate,
他们知道人们是被恶劣对待的。
they have known how to be treated bad.
但这是你的选择。
But it's your choice.
我记得很清楚，我说,
And I remember, it was so clear that I said,
我当然想和甘地和曼德拉在一起。
of course I want to be with Gandhi, with Mandela.
我钦佩这些人。
I admire these people.
我崇拜特蕾莎修女。
I admired Mother Teresa.
我想成为他们那样的人。
I want to be like them.
那他们做了什么呢？
So what did they do?
他们相信人是可以改变的。
They believed people can change.
这是我内在思维的一个巨大转变。
That was a huge shift in my thinking in my body.
人确实会变的。
People do change.
我记得当时在想，等一下。
And I remember thinking, wait a minute.
我不认为人真的可以改变。
I don't think people can really change.
再等一下。
Now, wait a minute again.
看看我，我正改变所有这些想法。
Look at me, I'm changing with all these thoughts.
当我意识到人是会变的,
So when I realized that people actually do change,
人们有能力以不同的方式看待事物时,
people have the capacity to see things differently,
那时我才意识到我是可以放手的。
that's when I realized I can let it go.
我感觉从洗手间到了一个有清新之地。
I felt like I moved from the bathroom to a place of air.
这就是爱在我身体里的感觉。
That's how love felt in my body.
我闻不到任何不好的味道。
I couldn't smell nothing bad.
就好像我在漂浮。
It was like I was floating.
而那是我心中的天堂。
And that was a paradise in my heart.
我想到了那些杀人犯，
I thought about the killers,
我应该对他们有慈心。
I should have compassion towards them.
想象一下，那个杀了100个人的人，
Imagine the person who killed 100 people,
他从孩子们身边夺走了他们的父母。
who have took away fathers and mothers from their kids.
当他们有一天醒来，意识到自己在做什么时，
What are they going to become when they wake up one day
他们会变成什么呢？
and they realize what they're doing?
一个向他们乞求生活的人吗？
Someone who begged them for life?
当我们出来的时候，就像世界末日一样。
When we came out, it was like end of the world.
有一百多万人被杀了。
A million people and more was killed.
我妈妈、爸爸、两个兄弟、奶奶
My mom, my father, my two brothers, my grandma
爷爷、邻居们以及
and my grandpa, neighbors,
我的同学还有最好的朋友都被杀了。
my schoolmates, my best friends.
那是世界末日。
It was the end of the world.
到处都是人们的尸体。
Everywhere was their bodies.
但是我的心已经变了。
But something have changed in my heart.
我内心很坚强。
I was strong inside.
我真的准备好以不同的方式面对生活了。
I was really ready to face life in a different way.
我骨瘦如柴。
I'm a skeleton.
只有65磅。
I'm 65 pounds.
但在内心深处，我感觉自己很高大，感觉自己更美丽。
But inside, I felt huge, I felt more beautiful.
我觉得每个人都是上帝的恩赐,
I felt like everybody was just a gift of God,
我只想服务他人，帮助他人，关心他人。
and I just wanted to serve, to help, and to care.
我第一次对我认为永远
For the first time I'm being grateful
理所当然的事情心存感激。
for things I took for granted forever.
我可以跟别人打招呼，而不会被人杀死。
And I can say hi to somebody without anyone killing me.
我记得在傍晚时分，暖风拂面。
And then I remember in evening, this nice wind.
树木摇曳，我能感觉风在我的身体里。
The trees are moving, I can feel the wind in my body.
我已经三个月没有这种感觉了。
I didn't feel this for three months.
我可以看见星星，可以看见月亮,
I can see the stars, I can see the moon,
而且我不用为此付任何代价。
and I don't have to pay for this.
我有没有过看着月亮，说,
Did I ever looked at the moon and said,
"哇，有月亮真好？"
wow, nice to have the moon?
没有。
No.
那是一种无法抗拒的爱和感激的感觉。
It was overwhelming feeling of love and appreciation.
我想向全世界大叫。
I wanted to scream to the whole world.
你看到它的美了吗？
Do you see the beauty?
头脑可以理解概念上的整体性,
The mind can understand conceptually wholeness,
但是只有坚强的人才能体验到整体性。
but only the hard can experience wholeness.
如果我们能容纳我们所经历的,
And the reward, if we can endure what we experience,
其回报是我们不只抓住了整体性，还感受到了它。
is that we don't just grasp oneness, we feel it.
你的大脑把事情看成非黑即白，
Your head sees things as black or white,
是非善恶分明，
wrong or right, bad or good.
头脑总是在曲直判断，总是失去平衡。
Head is always touching, always off balance.
我要等多久才能恢复清白？
How long do I have to wait for it to be white again?
你看不到并不代表它不存在。
Just because you can't see it doesn't mean it isn't there.
心灵比头脑更快，也更明智。
The heart is much faster and wiser than the head.
在心灵的眼睛里，
In the eyes of the heart,
黑白判断消失了，
black and white judgments disappear
因为心被一个更深的真理所平衡。
because the heart is balanced by a deeper truth.
伟大的灵性把只有用心才能体会到的
The great spirit spins together moments of profound beauty
深刻的美感的时刻编织在一起。
that can only be experienced with the heart.
我永远感激那间浴室。
I am forever grateful for that bathroom.
不是去看邪恶把人带到哪里,
To see where evil can take people,
而是去看爱能把人领向何方。
but to see also where love can take people.
要认识到人们的弱点,
Just realize the weakness of people,
但也认出我们每个人内心的力量。
but the strength that is within each one of us.
心让我拓展，挖掘我的内心,
To push me that far, to dig within my heart,
相信自己内心的直觉。
and to trust that instinct within.
当你能对这一切表示感谢，
And when you can give thanks for it all
无条件地去爱，那么你就自由了。
and love without conditions, then you will be free.
这就是心的力量。
That is the power of the heart.
生活中充满了挑战。
Life is full of challenges.
挑战和困难往往是
Challenges and hardships often times
强烈的热焰，
are the intense heat and fire that
让我们敞开心扉去发现以前我们
break us open to discover gifts, talents and capacities
从未发现的本自具足的天赋、才能和能力。
within us that we would have never discovered before.
就像可以燃烧的火柴一样，
So like a match that holds fire,
但直到它撞擦到什么东西前，是不会产生火焰的。
but until it strikes against something you have no flame.
通过与经验的摩擦，
By rubbing up against experience,
我们的心就会燃烧起来，
our heart comes aflame,
光和温暖就会从我们身上产生。
and light and warmth come from us.
你甚至可以对你想象中
You can even be grateful for things
对你没有任何好处的事情心存感激。
that you imagine that aren't any good for you.
那些你认为你并不真的想要的东西，
That you imagine that you don't really want,
或者你希望你不需要经历的事情。
or that you wish you hadn't had to experience.
即使在这样的时刻，大师们也会对生命说声谢谢,
Even in those moments, masters say thank you to life,
对上帝说声谢谢，对神圣的自我说声谢谢，
thank you to God, thank you to the divine self
因为他有了这次特殊的经历。
for this particular experience.
因为我知道，过不了多久，
Because I know that before too long
我将会看到已经融入到
I will see the extraordinary gift that
这场物质身接触中的非凡礼物。
has been folded into this physical encounter.
种族屠杀六个月后，
Six months after the genocide,
人们常常告诉我,
and people used to tell me,
你不能这么快就宽恕。
you can't forgive this quick.
高兴得也太早了。
It's too quick to be happy.
发生了这种事，你怎么还笑得出来。
You can't be smiling after what happened.
有时这真的让我
And that really kind of made me
不禁有点自我怀疑。
question a little bit sometimes.
我说，
I said,
我是不是出于生存机制而快乐和宽恕？
am I happy and forgiving out of surviving mechanism?
我是不是有一天会被压垮？
Am I going to crush one day?
很多人告诉我，有一天，如果你看到他们,
Which many people told me, on one day, if you see them,
你会回到愤怒的状态。
you will go back to the anger.
我说，真的吗？
I said, really?
等着瞧吧。
Let me see.
我去监狱看那个
So I went to prison to see the person
杀了我妈妈和我弟弟的人，
who have killed my mom and my brother,
我本来是不会去见他的。
whom I would not have gone to meet him.
这对我没有一点好处。
It didn't serve me one bit.
我去那里只是想看看我的感受。
So I went there just to really see how I feel.
我了解到监狱长
And I have learned the head of the jail
是我父亲的朋友，
is a friend of my father
他失去了妻子和五个孩子。
who lost his wife and like five children.
我知道他会为我开门。
So I knew he would open the door for me.
你可以打他，
You can hit him,
可以做你想做的任何事，
you can do whatever you want,
因为我就在这里，
because I'm here now,
我会保护你的。
I will protect you.
这样可以减轻你的痛苦。
So ease up your pain.
他把那个人带来了。
And he brought the man.
我记得他。
I remember him.
他以前是个老师。
He used to be a teacher.
他就像我的父亲。
He was like a father to me.
他有和我一样大的孩子。
He had kids my age.
我以前常去看他们，
I used to visit them,
和他们家人一起吃午饭。
and have lunch with the family.
是他干的吗！？
Now that's him who did that?
我崩溃了，哭了。
I just broke down and cried.
我真的是出于对他和
And I truly cried out of compassion
他的家人的怜悯而哭泣。
towards him and his family.
我宽恕你。
I forgive you.
这并不是说，哦，我计划过要说这些话。
It wasn't like, oh, I planned to say these words.
有些事我想表达一下,
There's something I wanted to express,
不过我无法用言语来表达。
and I couldn't find words to say it fully.
我希望他能从我这里得自由。
I wanted him to be free from me.
而不是去想，哦，她在生我的气。
Not to think, oh, she's mad at me.
你知道，我不能什么都不做。
You know, I can't do nothing.
我只是想给他一个机会
I just wanted him to have a chance
从他自己的心去经历他自己的旅程,
to go through his own journey from his own heart,
而不是因为有人生他的气,
not because somebody is angry at him,
或者有人把他关进了监狱。
or someone put him in a prison.
你到底怎么了？
What is wrong with you?
监狱长很生气。
And the head of the jail was so mad.
你到底怎么了！
What is wrong with you, huh?
你不知道他对我们做了什么吗？！
You do not know what he did to us?
你不爱你的父母，嗯？
You do not love your parents, huh?
难道你忘了吗？
You forget?
我忘了在那里的那个人,
I forgot that the man was there,
实际上他也失去了家人。
and actually who lost his family, too.
我真的感到很难过。
And I really felt bad.
你宽恕了一个杀人犯？
You forgive a killer?
你到底怎么了？
What is wrong with you?
天啊，我为什么要宽恕他？
Oh my God, why did I forgive him?
但我做了，我想这么做。
But I did, I wanted to.
我想让他得自由。
I wanted to free him.
但这感觉更像是软弱，感觉像是，
But it felt more like weakness, it felt like,
在某个地方，我知道我做的是对的。
somewhere I knew it was the right thing.
这是最可怕的故事。
It's the most horrifying tale.
然而，她和许多经历过种族灭绝的人,
And yet, she and many people living through that genocide,
在他们的心中找到了宽恕和继续前进的信念。
have found it in their hearts to forgive and to move on.
宽恕就是一切。
Forgiveness is everything.
当我想到宽恕，
When I think of forgiveness,
我就会为它的存在而感激涕零。
I'm brought to weep with gratitude that it exists.
宽恕并不意味着
Now, forgiveness doesn't mean that
你会容忍别人的行为。
you're condoning someone else's behavior.
这一点非常重要。
This is a really important point.
宽恕仅仅意味着
Forgiveness merely means that
你将自己从
you're freeing yourself up from
你所持有的能量块、
the energy blocks that you're holding,
你所携带的怨恨中解放出来。
those resentments that you're carrying.
有一首歌，一首福音歌曲。
There's a song, a Gospel song.
它这样唱到，
And it says,
把你的重担交给主，
take your burden to the Lord
把它们留在那里。
and leave them there.
把它们留在那里，哦，把它们留在那里。
Leave them there, oh, leave them there.
把你的重担交给主，把它们留在那里。
Take your burden to the Lord and leave them there.
如果你信祂，莫怀疑，
If you trust Him, never doubt,
祂一定会带你出来。
he will surely bring you out.
把你的重担交给主，把它们留在那里，
Take your burden to the Lord and leave them-- now,
就是这样，有很多人
there is that, and there are people
唱得如此热情，如此自信。
that sing that with such fervor and such confidence.
而这些人也承担了他们的重担,
And those are the same people who take their burden,
说我的重担在那里，
say there my burdens,
然后他们站起来，带着负担走了。
and then they get up and take the burden with them.
然后他们..
And they go...
我们怎样才能与心相连呢？
How can we connect with the heart?
出发点就是你此时此刻拥有的一切。
Well, your starting point is all you ever have, this moment.
我们一直都很忙。
We are so busy all the time.
我们没有时间，没有空间，没有心的静默。
There's no time, no space, no silence for the heart.
除非你真的能到大自然中去,
Unless you actually can be out in nature,
感受鸟儿的歌唱，
and experience the birds singing,
感受树木和蓝天，
and the trees and the blue sky,
否则你就脱离了伟大的灵性存在，
you are divorced from the great spiritual being
而我觉得它就在我们周边
that I feel is all around us.
而我是如此幸运，
And I've been so lucky to spend
能在大自然中独自度过好几个月。
months and months on my own in nature.
然后你就能成为一个完整的人，
Then you can become a whole human being
有心、有脑、有灵魂,
with heart, and brain, and spirit,
相互联系，完整无缺。
all connected and whole.
这就是为什么人们冥想或祈祷,
That's why maybe people meditate or pray,
因为他们需要那个空间、那个时刻
because they need that space, that moment
去听从内心的声音。
when you listen to the heart.
每场风暴的中心都有一个肚脐大小的洞，
Every storm has a hole in the center the size of a navel
从中一只海鸥可以安静地飞过。
through which a gull can fly in silence.
因此你变得平静。
And so you become calm.
你必须变得平静。
You must become calm.
如果你不知道该做什么，那就什么都不做。
If you don't know what to do, do nothing.
不要用琐事来填满时间，什么也不要做。
Don't fill your time with trivia, simply do nothing.
坐下即好。
Simply sit.
深呼吸。
Breathe.
所有的传统都在讲
All the traditions speak about the value
冥想、反思和沉思的价值,
of meditation, reflection, contemplation,
它们都以呼吸为中心。
which all center on breathing.
为什么？
Why?
因为呼吸让我们回归当下的平安。
Because breath restores us to the safety of the moment.
现在你要比平时呼吸得
Now you want to breathe a little deeper and a little
更深更慢一点。
slower than you normally would.
吸气四五秒，
About a four or five second on the in-breath,
呼气四五秒。
and four or five seconds on the out-breath.
不过不要屏住呼吸，你只是
But you don't hold your breath,
找到一个好的节奏和速度，
you just get a nice rhythm, that pace,
把你的紧张感保持在心脏的区域。
holding your tension in the area of the heart.
把你的觉知带到你的心里。
Bring your awareness to your heart.
把你有意识的觉知带到你的心里。
Bring your conscious awareness into your heart.
也许你能听到。
And you may be able maybe to hear.
我一直向我的心祈求指引。
I ask my heart all the time for guidance.
你的心有一个很好的方式来告诉你，
Your heart has a very good way to tell you
你是否走在正确的道路上。
whether you're in a good path or not.
这就是所谓的热情。
It's called enthusiasm.
我让周围的一切进入我的内心，
I let in whatever's around me,
我问自己，我现在的活力在哪里？
and I ask, where's the aliveness now?
当我和孩子们玩耍时，
When I'm playing with the kids,
当我和丈夫做爱时，
when I make love to my husband,
当我读一本好书的时候，
when I read a good book,
当我写作的时候，我觉得那些角色
when I'm writing and I feel that the character
变成了一个个人，并和我说话，
becomes a person and talks to me,
然后我的心也感觉飘飘然，
then my heart also feels fluttering,
充满欢笑，充满喜悦。
and with laughter,with joy.
为什么一切都要那么严肃呢？
Why everything has to be so serious?
玩得开心很重要。
It's very important to have fun.
即使是你正在做的事情中间，
Even the middle of something that you are doing that
需要有大量的纪律性。
requires a lot of discipline.
因此，连接你的心，成为一个孩子吧！
And so to connect to your heart, become a child.
我亲爱的朋友乔治来希腊了。
My dear friend George came to Greece.
这家伙是个亿万富翁。
This guy is a billionaire.
而且他块头很大。
And he is very big.
他开始和我说话，我说：
He started talking, and I said--
听着。
Listen.
如果你想要和我谈，就跟我来。
If you want to talk with me, come with me.
我带他去了雅典市中心，
I took him out in the central of Athens
那里有蹦床。
where we have a trampoline.
伙计，除非你在蹦床上跟着我，
We're not going to talk business
否则我不会和你谈生意的。
unless you follow me on the trampoline, man.
不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no.
来吧，来吧，伙计，我们一起跳。
Yes, yes, yes, together.
我才不要玩蹦床。
I'm not going on a trampoline.
脱掉你衣服和鞋子可真不容易啊，伙计。
You're a difficult guy to get undressed, man.
他这辈子
He came up on the trampoline
第一次玩蹦床,
for the first time in his life,
我们开始一起跳，
and we started jumping together,
上跳下跳，左蹦右蹦。
up and down, up and down.
他有140公斤，不是吗？
140 kilos, no?
嘿，只要你稍微训练一下，
Hey, you could become a champion
你就可以成为冠军。
if you train a little bit.
参加下一届奥运会，好吗？
Next Olympic games, OK?
我来当你的经纪人！
I will be your manager, man!
哇，你真不赖，伙计！
Wow, what a good boy you are, man!
我就喜欢这样！
That's the way I like it!
他那么开心，像个小孩子。
He was so happy, like a little child.
我们心中的小孩被藏起来了。
The child is hidden.
每个人都是孩子，即使他是亿万富翁。
Everybody's a child, even him, who is a billionaire.
孩子说，你好，我在这里。
And the child is saying, hello, I'm here.
但是我们想，哦，我们已经长大了,
But we think, oh, we are grown up,
我们不会听这个孩子的。
we're not going to listen to this child.
因为这个孩子有幼稚的梦想。
Because this child has childish dreams.
所以我们忘记了孩子。
And so we forget the child.
从我们忘记孩子的那一刻起,
And from the moment that we forget the child,
我们认为孩子会忘记我们。
we think the child is going to forget us.
不是的。
No.
内在小孩是不会忘记我们的。
The child is not going to forget us.
这个孩子会一直在心里告诉我们：
This child will be here always,
”你好，我在这里。
hello, I'm here.
我在跟你说话。
I'm talking to you.
你能听我说吗？“
Can you listen?
然后我们说：
And then we say,
“闭嘴。
shut up.
我不想听你的。“
I don't want to listen to you.
但是当你面对死亡的那一天,
But the day that you're facing death,
这个孩子会在那里，
this child will be there,
再一次问你：
and are going to ask you again,
“你为什么不听我的？”
why didn't you listen to me?
然后你必须回答。
And then you have to answer.
你的答案将决定你在地狱还是天堂。
And your answer will be your hell or your heaven.
幼稚和童真的区别
The difference between being childish and childlike
就是幼稚会减少你的心量，
is that being childish reduces our world
让我们变得以自我为中心。
and returns us to being self-centered.
童真让我们充满好奇心。
Being childlike returns us to wonder.
如果实践下面这个练习的话，
It's wonderful to be like a child
像个孩子一样是很美妙的。
if you still can practice this.
当我在新地方、新的城市或新地区时,
When I'm in new places, or new cities, or new areas,
我就像爱丽丝漫游仙境一样。
I'm as Alice in Wonderland.
然后心就又打开了。
Then the heart goes open again.
我觉得我的心兴奋极了。
And then I feel my heart exploding.
我能感觉到心的热度。
You know, I feel the heat of the heart.
与心灵保持一致
And it is wonderfully liberating and empowering
是种奇妙的解放和赋能，
to be aligned with the heart,
它是所有创造的基础。
that which underlies all creation.
就是在这个时候，你经常会发现有益的因素
And it is then that often you find helpful factors
突然闯入你的生活中，
coming into your life out of nowhere,
而这些同步性事件
and those are synchronistic events that
通常是确认
usually are confirmation that
你与更深源头的联系。
you are connected to that deeper level.
同步性这个词是卡尔·荣格创造的。
Synchronicity this word that was created by Carl Jung.
当事情看起来是巧合时,
When something appears to be a coincidence,
但你知道事情远非如此。
but you know that there's more to it than that.
例如，你在恰当的时间接到一个电话。
For example, you get a phone call just at the right moment.
一些有益于你的事情发生着，
Something that becomes helpful factor,
而你无法从因果关系上解释那是如何发生的。
and you cannot explain causally how that happened.
同步性是个奇迹。
Synchronicity is a miracle.
你唯一能做的就是
The only thing that you can do is
对同步性持开放态度。
to be open to synchronicity.
这就像一个过滤器掉了下来，
It is as if a filter drops away,
我们注意到同步性无处不在。
and we notice that synchronicity is all around us.
这不是一个偶然的宇宙。
That this isn't an accidental universe.
当我们在等医生的消息时,
When we were waiting to hear from the doctors,
我拿着一件克里斯蒂娜的夹克。
I had one of Christina's jackets.
我把手伸进口袋，
And I reached into the pockets
从幸运饼干里拿出了一张幸运符。
and I pulled out a fortune from a fortune cookie.
里面写着“我们必须永远怀着旧时的记忆和年轻的希望”。
We must always have old memories and young hopes.
这对我们来说是她离开的信号。
And that was a sign for us that she was gone.
我立刻觉得这就像..
And immediately I just thought this was like--
最后一条信息。
A final message.
她给我们的最后信息。
Her final message to us.
我的意思是，旧的记忆是
I mean, the old memories were the old memories
与克里斯蒂娜的记忆。
with her, with Christina.
还有，年轻人的希望，或者乐观主义,
And the young hopes, or the optimism,
她才21岁。
she was 21 years old.
她展望了她的整个人生。
She looked ahead to her whole life.
对我来说，这是在告诉我们，
To me it was telling us
我们要继续她未竟的事业，
that we have to pick up where she left off,
即使我已经不是21岁了。
even though I'm not 21 anymore.
我必须接受这种理念，
I have to adopt that philosophy
并努力不辜负年轻时对未来的期望，
and try to live up to the young hopes
你可以拥有的，
for the future that you can have,
你可以在世界中有所作为。
and that you can make a difference in the world.
同步性很大程度上是由于直觉，
Synchronicity is largely due to intuition,
我们最终在恰当的时间出现在恰当的地方，
where we end up in the right place at the right time
因为我们有内心的指引。
because of that inner guidance.
在我们做的其他实验中，
In other experiments we've done,
我们看到心可以
we see that the heart can know
提前20秒左右就知道信息。
the information about 20 seconds before hand.
但在现实生活中，我们的直觉
But in real life, our intuition's
不受这些实验方案的限制。
not limited by these experimental protocols.
我认为我们必须小心，不要说，
And I think we have to be careful not to say that,
嗯，直觉只会发生在事件前20秒。
well, intuition is only 20 seconds before an event.
因为我们知道在现实世界中,
Because we know in the real world,
在一个事件真正发生之前，可能几小时，
it can be hours and sometimes even days
有时甚至几天前，我们就有直觉。
before an event actually occurs.
大多数人会立刻想到去拉斯维加斯，
Most people instantly think about going to Las Vegas
以及去参加赌博什么的。
and gambling or something.
如果直觉真的像我说的那样有效,
If intuition really works as I'm suggesting,
那真是我们自己的灵性在与我们合作。
it's really our own spirit working with us.
无论你怎么称呼它，我们的高我或
So it's not always in our best behalf from that interaction
我们的灵魂之间的互动
between our higher self, or our soul,
并不总是最符合我们的利益。
whatever you want to call it.
每种文化都有称呼直觉的说法。
Every culture has their own name for it.
我们去拉斯维加斯，总是赢。
That we go to Las Vegas and just win all the time.
直觉是我们最好的朋友。
So intuition is really our own best friend.
它真的是我们每时每刻的内在指导。
It's really the moment to moment inner guidance.
我们有过那种感觉，
You know, when we get that feeling that something's
觉得有些事情不对劲，或者我们不该做什么。
just not right, or we shouldn't do something.
也可以是一种积极的感觉，
Or it can be a positive feeling that we really
应该做些什么，或者去某个地方。
should do something, or go to a certain place.
我记得种族屠杀发生的前一天。
I remember the day before the genocide happened.
我哥哥回到家，他和朋友们待了一天,
My brother came home, he spent a day with his friends,
他告诉我们，他听到一个谣言，
and he told us that he heard a rumor
说他们将在那天晚上杀光所有图西人。
that they were going to kill every Tutsi that night.
而我们，我们的家人，在名单列表上。
And we were, our family, on the list.
我不能仅仅因为你听到了一个谣言就让家人离开。
I cannot move the family just because you heard a rumor.
如果这是真的，到了早上..
What if it's true, and in the morning--
别说了。
Stop it.
不要害怕。
No fear.
相信上帝就好，忘了这个谣言吧。
Just trust in God and forget about it.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我们该走了。
We should move.
这很重要。
This is so important.
10分钟就到了，我们可以直接坐船，
It's 10 minutes away, we can just take the boat,
如果没事的话，明早再来。
and come back in the morning if nothing.
我知道，但我们也必须相信我们的父亲。
I know, but we must trust our father, too.
我知道，你说得对。
I know, you're right.
我们应该这么做，对吧？
We should, right?
因为他总是有很好的判断力。
Because he always has good judgment.
我们应该离开。
We should.
我心里很清楚，
It was so clear in my heart
我的决定是离开这个国家。
that my decision was to move away from the country.
到了早上，一切都太迟了。
By the morning, it was too late.
他们封锁了所有的边境。
They had blocked all the borders.
这个教训彻底改变了我的心。
That lesson completely changed my heart forever.
当我有这种感觉的时候，我会倾听自己的心声,
Now when I have that feeling, I do listen to my heart,
而不管别人说什么。
no matter who is saying what.
我必须听从自己的内心。
I have to listen to my heart.
如果不相信心,
Well, if you don't trust the heart,
你要相信什么呢？
what are you going to trust?
我相信心是我们唯一可以信任的东西。
I believe the heart is the only thing we can trust.
当我们达到这样的地步，
When we get to the point where we have experienced
即我们经历了自己内心的转变，
this transformation within ourselves,
活在爱中而不是恐惧中，
where living from love rather than fear
改变了我们的生活环境,
has transformed our own life circumstances,
那么我们就成为了管道，成为了容器。
then we become channels, we become vessels.
我们有道德权威，
We have the moral authority by which
可以为地球陈述这种可能性。
to state that possibility for the planet.
就在她去世前，我告诉她，
Just before she passed, I was telling her
我已经好几年没工作了,
that I'd been off work for a couple of years,
我们退休了。
and we retired.
我正在寻找有意义的
And I was kind of looking for something
事情来度过我的余生，
meaningful to do with the rest of my life,
因为我还年轻。
because I was still young.
她说，哦，总会找到的。
And she said, oh, something will come along.
到时候你就知道了。
You'll know it when it comes along.
她去世的时候，我立刻就知道了
And when she passed, I knew instantly
我们必须继续她的工作。
that we had to continue her work.
所以我们成立了基金会，
And so we started the foundation,
克里斯蒂娜切斯特曼纪念基金会，
the Christina Chesterman Memorial Foundation,
只是在她已经留下的遗产的基础上再接再厉。
to just build on the legacy that she left already.
当你发自内心地生活时，
As you live from the heart
越来越多的人开始发自内心地生活，
and more humans begin to live from the heart,
这会产生连锁反应。
that has a ripple effect.
它从你所在的地方泛起涟漪，
It ripples out from where you are,
然后再回到你身边。
and then you get it back.
每一天你都在努力。
Every day you work at it.
每一天你都要走到心里去。
Every day you go to the heart.
每天心都跟我说话。
Every day you speak to me.
事实上，我每天早上都以
In fact, I start each morning
我们所说的 "心锁 "起来。
with what we call a heart lock in.
只是连贯起来，真正向自己
Just getting coherent and really sending myself
发送几分钟的爱和欣赏，
love and appreciation for a few minutes,
从一个更连贯、更有条理、
to start my day from a more coherent,
更有联系的角度开始我的一天。
composed, and connected perspective.
然后一整天你得重新启动它。
Then throughout the day you've got to kind of reboot that.
所以它确实在生命中形成了一种流动。
So really it's developing kind of a flow through life.
所有我称之为中间时刻的东西，
So all the in-between moments, as I call them,
比如在这里和餐厅之间,
like in between here and the lunch room,
或者在这里和复印机之间。
or between here and the photocopier.
那些中间时刻是完美的机会，
Those in-between moments are perfect opportunities
让我们在欣赏中呼吸，
to breathe in that appreciation,
或在内心的轻松状态中呼吸。
or that state of inner ease.
我的意思是，反正我们也得呼吸,
I mean, we have to breathe anyway,
所以我们不妨让它更有效。
so we might as well make it more effective.
如果我们足够冷静，
And if we can calm down enough,
我们就可以聆听智慧。
we can listen to the wisdom.
我们学习如何成为好邻居、好访客。
We learn how to be good neighbors, good visitors.
如何成为好父母。
How to be good parents.
如何成为好员工，好老师。
How to be good workers, good teachers.
我们学习如何成为好公民。
We learn how to be good citizens.
善良的人类。
Good human beings.
因为我们倾听。
Because we listen.
不要试图把我们的声音放进去。
And not try to put our voices in it.
听就是了。
Just listen.
心是我的导师。
The heart is my guru.
在我见过的所有大师中，这位才是真正的大师。
For all gurus I've met, this one is the real one.
问你的心任何问题。
Ask your heart any question.
我是谁？
Who am I?
我想要什么？
What do I want?
我的人生目标是什么？
What's my purpose in life?
我在一个好朋友身上看重的品质是什么？
What are the qualities that I look for in a good friend?
在一段良好的关系中，
What are the qualities that I contribute to
我呈现出了哪些品质？
in a good relationship?
我的独特技能和才能是什么？
What are my unique skills and talents?
我该如何利用它为人类服务？
How do I use this to serve humanity?
你的心知道所有的答案。
Your heart knows all the answers.
我还是觉得很迷茫。
I still feel lost.
我不知道我的人生该怎么办了。
I don't know what to do with my life anymore.
把这个问题放在心上。
Take the question to your heart.
我一直都是。
I have been.
但我得不到任何答案。
I'm not getting any answers.
你只在想而已，它比实际情况更难。
You're thinking, it's harder than it really is.
只要跟随你心中的那份轻盈,
Just follow that lightness in your heart,
最终它将引领你走向有意义的人生。
and that will eventually lead you to a life of purpose.
我们心中的一些最大疑问就像
Some of the biggest questions of the heart
一条路一样展开,而不是由答案铺就。
unfold as a path, not an answer.
追随我们的生命力，
Following our aliveness
而不执著于它将成为什么。
without attaching what it will become.
不是为了成为诗人，
Not to become a poet,
而是通过问题和生活的表达活出生命。
but I'm brought alive by the questions and the life of expression.
不是为了成为歌手，
Not to become a singer,
而是通过从你身上发出的声音活出生命。
but to be brought alive by voice coming out of you.
我们开始从中心去连接，
We begin to connect from our center
而不仅仅是表面人格。
and not just from surface personality.
这是一种完全不同的在世生活的方式。
It's a whole different way of moving through the world.
当一个人像这样在世界上穿梭时,
And when one moves through the world like this,
当我们开始像这样穿越世界时,
and when we begin to move through the world like this,
然后不断扩展的善的领域，
then the realm of ever expanding good,
即天堂的另一个名字，
another name for heaven,
便开始显现在我们的星球上。
begins to be revealed on our planet.
我们看不到未来，但是心看到了它。
We cannot see tomorrow's sky, but the heart sees it.
我们将被指示
And we will be directed
在未来应该如何行动。
as to how we should act in tomorrow's sky.
更有可能的是，我们已经知道了。
More than likely, we already know.
如果我们不知道，心会告诉我们，如果我们谛听的话。
But if we don't, the heart will tell us, if we listen.
这是给你的，亲爱的。
This is for you, sweetheart.